<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="alignment">
    <title>Alignment</title>
    <shortdesc>While alignment is a feature shared with a lot of CAT tools, its use can vary from
        very difficult to extremely easy so you should choose your TMS carefully.</shortdesc>
    <conbody>
        <p>The alignment tool matches the source and target language files side-by-side to determine
            which pairs belong together. The result is a parallel text (<i>bitext</i>).</p>
        <p>You use it if you have the translated versions of your documents, but the translation
            wasn’t performed in a CAT tool so you don't have a translation memory. Now these
            documents need to be updated or changed across the languages and you want to retain the
            existing content, style and terminology. In addition, you wish to reduce costs, because
            there are a lot of repetitions and matches.</p>
        <p>
            <fig id="fig_pt5_mwk_jtb">
                <title>Alignment in XTM</title>
                <image href="../images/Alignment.jpg" scale="60" id="image_qt5_mwk_jtb">
                    <alt>Alignment in XTM</alt>
                </image>
            </fig>
        </p>
        <p>TMSs are of great help here because this is a built-in feature. All you have to do is go
            to <i>TM </i>> <i>Align</i>, upload two documents (in source and target languages), run
            the alignment and analyze the results. In XTM you get an Excel file with texts in two
            columns and a probability score. </p>
        <p>
            <fig id="fig_wg5_pwk_jtb">
                <title>Result of XTM alignment</title>
                <image href="../images/Aligned%20docs.jpg" scale="60" id="image_xg5_pwk_jtb">
                    <alt>Result of XTM alignment</alt>
                </image>
            </fig>
        </p>
        <p>You need to check it thoroughly and, if everything is done, upload the file in the <i>TM
                import</i> tab. Then, the translation memory is updated automatically.</p>
        <p>XTM <i>Align</i> creates two Excel spreadsheets for each alignment: one with <i>90+</i>
            probability of accurate alignment (quick check and upload) and the other with all
            texts.</p>
        <p>The only disadvantage is that the <i>Align</i> feature in XTM is shared with all of the
            customers on the cloud so sometimes it takes a long time for the file to be returned. It
            also takes longer if you build a dictionary for a new language pair.</p>
        <p>
            <note id="note_psz_33h_3tb">In XTM the <i>Align</i> feature is only available for the
                enterprise account (it is not available for freelance or group accounts).</note>
        </p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
